Hardita Kurniawan

Back-End Developer

+6282233786565

- harditakurniawan.github.io/portfolio/
- Magelang, Indonesia

EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer

PT. Mitra Bhakti Informasi

11/2022 - Present

- Collaborated with a team of 9 developers to create a robust loyalty points platform.
- Collaborate with the QA team to test applications in the staging environment.
- Participated in daily stand-up meetings and sprint planning sessions as part of an agile development team.
- Implementing a microservice architecture using NestJs and Kafka for a loyalty points platform.
- Implementing a microservice architecture using Express Js by utilizing RESTful API as a communication protocol between services.
- · Experience with containerization technologies like Docker.
- Optimizing large-scale queries through batch techniques, resulting in enhanced query success rates.
- Implemented cache techniques using Redis to significantly improve query speed.

Backend Developer

PT. Dengan Senang Hati

09/2021 - 08/2024

- Be responsible for designing and building backend applications, third-party data integration, data API and backend systems.
- Write code that is clear, concise and easily understood by others.
- Framework experience: NestJS, Express Js, Laravel, Vue Js.
- Work with relational databases, NoSQL databases and Type ORM to create efficient data models and gueries.
- Develop and implement RESTful APIs based on functional documentation.
- Utilise version control systems, particularly Git, to manage codebase and collaborate with other developers effectively.
- Implement security and data protection, such as encryption and user authentication.
- · Collaborate with front-end developers to integrate APIs.
- Code reviewing, testing, and debugging to ensure all features work properly.

Junior Web Developer

PT. Indosat Ooredoo

03/2020 - 08/2021

- Create web application using Laravel and its blade template, MySQL and javascript within 3 months
- · Participated in daily stand-up meetings and sprint planning

SUMMARY

Experienced backend developer with a 4-year proven track record in the industry. Recognized for being a fast learner and dedicated professional. Highly motivated to continuously expand knowledge and skills to stay up-to-date with the latest technology advancements. Strong ability to quickly adapt to new programming languages and confidently tackle any technical challenge.

SKILLS

Javascript	Expert
NestJs	Expert
Express Js	Expert
PHP	Advanced
Laravel	Advanced
Arduino Programming	Advanced
MySQL	Advanced
MongoDB	Advanced
GIT	Advanced
Docker	Advanced
PostgreSQL	Intermediate
HTML	Intermediate
CSS	Intermediate
VueJs	Intermediate

LANGUAGES

English	Intermediate
Indonesia	Native

sessions as part of an agile development team.

- Collaborate with the QA team to test applications in the staging environment.
- Framework experience: Laravel.
- Work with relational databases and Eloquent ORM to create efficient data models and queries.

EDUCATION

Electrical Engineering
Telkom University
08/2015 - 08/2019
Bachelor Degree